Inventory of the Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection, 1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
- Series 1: Authors Files
  - Gagnon, John H., Physical Strength, once of Significance, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, Eleanor and Franklin Revisited, undated (Box 8)
  - Gale, D. and Shapley, L. S., College Admissions and the Stability of Marriage, undated (Box 8)
  - Gallagher, Dorothy, If Happiness isn't the Measure of Success in Marriage, What is?, undated (Box 8)
  - Gardiner, Jean, New Left Review: The Role of Domestic Labour, undated (Box 9)
  - Gardner, Jo-Ann E., The Psychology and the Pyschological Effects of Discrimination or Psychology is Part of the Problem, undated (Box 9)
  - , Pennsylvania NOW: Changing the Rules of the Game in Politics, undated (Box 9)
  - , Sesame Street and Sex-Role Stereotypes, undated (Box 9)
  - , What Effect should the Feminist Movement have on Higher Education, undated (Box 9)
  - Gardner, Gerald H. F., Discrimination on the Basis of Sex in Advertising and Recruiting for Jobs Requiring Ability in Mathematics, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Garrison, Dee, The Tender Technicians: The Feminization of Public Librarianship 1876-1905, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Geiger, Kent, Elements and Types in Soviet Marriage, undated (Box 9)
  - George, Alexander, Power as a Compensatory Value for Political Leaders, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Gershon, Karen, Misc., 1973 (Box 9)
  - Gillespie, Dair L., Who has the Power? The Marital Struggle, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Gillies, Raymond, Images of Man, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Gilman, Charlotte Perkins, The Released Energy of Women, undated (Box 9)
  - Gilman, Richard, The FemLib Case Against Sigmund Freud, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Ginet, Sally, Cook as Is, undated (Box 9)
  - Ginsburg, Ruth B., Gender in the Supreme Court: The 1973-74 Terms, undated (Box 9)
  - Gold, Alice Ross, You've Come a Long Way, Baby, But…Changing Beliefs and Values Relevant to Women's Achievement, 1975-76 (Box 9)
  - , What Psychologists Know and Don't Know about Sex Differences, undated (Box 9)
  - , Contraceptive Method and Female Sexual Arousal, undated (Box 9)
  - Goldberg, Marilyn P., The Economic Exploitation of Women, 1973 (Box 9)
  - , Women in the Soviet Economy, undated (Box 9)
  - Gordon, Ann D. and Buble, Mari Jo and Schrom, Nancy E., Women in American Society, undated (Box 9)
  - Gordon, Michael and Schankweiler, Penelope J., Different Equals Less: Female Sexuality in Recent Marriage Manuals, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Gornick, Vivian, The Woman's Movement in Crisis: Let's Stop the Infighting!, undated (Box 9)
  - , The Next Great Moment in History is Theirs, undated (Box 9)
  - , The Light of Liberation can be Blinding, undated (Box 9)
  - , In Any Terms She Shall Choose, undated (Box 9)
  - , Introduction with B. K. Moran, undated (Box 9)
  - Gove, Walter, Adult Sex-Roles and Mental Illness, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Graham, Alma, Non-Sexist Language Guidelines, undated (Box 9)
  - Graham, Patricia Albjerg, Women in Academe, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Grasso, Ella, Misc., undated (Box 9)
  - Greatest Source of Growth in the Labor Force (Not Just Female Labor Force) is the Married Woman,, undated (Box 9)
  - Green, Gwen, Proposal and Syllabus for a Course, undated (Box 9)
  - Greenbaum, Marcia L., Adding 'Kenntris' to 'Kirche, Kuche und Kinder', undated (Box 9)
  - Greene, Roberta, Til Divorce do you Part, undated (Box 9)
  - Greene, Thomas, A Report to the President from the Committee on the Status of Professional Women at Yale, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Greenfield, Sidney, Love and Marriage in Modern America: A Functional Analysis, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Griffin, Susan, Rape: The American Crime, undated (Box 10)
  - Griffiths Hearing,, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Grubb and McCoy, Love's Labor Lost: New Conceptions of Maternity Leaves, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Guitar, Mary Anne, "Property Power" Book of the Month Club, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Guttentag, Marcia, Misc., undated (Box 10)
  - , Subjectivity and its Use in Evaluation Research, undated (Box 10)
  - Gutwillig, J. et al, The Equal Rights Amendment - Senator Ervin's Minority Report and the Yale Law Journal, 1970 (Box 10)
  - , Recognition of Economic Contribution of Homemakers and Protection of Children in Divorce Law and Practice, undated (Box 10)
  - Hacker, Helen Mayer, The New Burdens of Masculinity, undated (Box 10)
  - , Women as a Minority Group, undated (Box 10)
  - Halonen, Kae, Man's World and Welcome to it, undated (Box 10)
  - Hamburg, David A. and Lunde, Donald, Sex Hormones in the Development of Sex Differences in Human Behavior, undated (Box 10)
  - Hammel, Lisa, We are the A's: Associate, Assistant, Adjunct, Acting, undated (Box 10)
  - Hannerz, UIF, Growing up Male (from Soulside), undated (Box 10)
  - Hardin, Garrett, The Tragedy of the Commons Revisited, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Hardwick, E., Women '…are demanding equal rights in something that is itself losing ground as a fulfillment', undated (Box 10)
  - Harmon, Sasha, Attitudes toward Women in the Criminal Process, undated (Box 10)
  - Harris, Ann Sutherland, The Second Sex in Academe, 1970 (Box 10)
  - , Women in College Art Departments and Museums, undated (Box 10)
  - Harris, Bertha, Misc., undated (Box 10)
  - Havemann, Joel, Education Report/Pending bill Could Revolutionize Federal Programs for Higher Education, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Hart, Nancy, Actress Presents an Evening With Gertrude Stein, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Hartford Courant, Educators Back Action Against Bias, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Hartley, Ruth E., Sex-Role Pressures and the Socialization of the Male Child, 1959 (Box 11)
  - , Current Patterns in Sex Roles: Children's Perspectivesq, undated (Box 11)
  - Hartman, Susan M., The Paradox of Women's Progress 1820-1920, undated (Box 11)
  - Haymes, Howard, Postwar Writing and the Literature of the Women's Liberation Movement, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Hearn, Thomas K., Jesus was a Sissy After All, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Heide, Wilma Scott, National Organization for Women, undated (Box 11)
  - , What's Wrong with a Male-Dominated Society, undated (Box 11)
  - Heilburn, Carolyn, The Masculine Wilderness of the American Novel, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Hein, Hilde, A Second Look at the Second Sex: the Institutionalization of Otherness, undated (Box 11)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, A Clean, Well-Lighted Place, undated (Box 11)
  - Henley, Nancy M., The Politics of Touch, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Hernandez, Aileen, Files of Race and Sex Discrimination, 1971 (Box 11)
  - , Revolution: From the Doll's House to the White House, undated (Box 11)
  - Hernandez, Lisa, Marilyn Monroe: Sex Goddess, Lonely Girl, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Herskovits, The Myth of the Negro Past, undated (Box 11)
  - Herstein, Sheila R., Prominent Victorian Women and Feminism: Selected Views, 1972 (Box 11)
  - , Historical Newspapers: 1853-1975, undated (Box 11)
  - Hochstein, Denise, A Brief Analysis of the Sociological Aspect of Suicide Amongst Women Physicians, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Hoffman, D. T., Psychotherapy as an Agent of Patriarchy, undated (Box 11)
  - Hoffman, Lois Wladis, A Re-examination of the Fear of Success, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Hogeland, Ronald W., The Female Appendage: Feminine Lifestyles in America, 1820-1860, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Hollander, Alan Roy, US District Court Document, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Hollander, Harriet E., The Impact od Gender Associated Irrationality on Women in Higher Education, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Hooke, Ruth, University without Walls, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Horn, John L. and Knott, Paul D., Activist Youth of 1960's: Summary and Prognosis, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Horner, Matina, A bright woman is caught in a double bind. In achievement-oriented situations she worries not only about failure but also about success, 1969 (Box 12)
  - , A Psychological significance of success in competitive achievement situations: A threat as well as a promise, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Hornig, Lilli S., A Proposal for Preparing Women for Professional Leadership, 1973 (Box 12)
  - , Morning Mail: Sex Discrimination in Higher Education, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Howe, Florence and Trecker, Janice L., Educating Women: No More Sugar and Spice, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Howe, Florence, Sexual Stereotypes Start Early, 1971 (Box 12)
  - , Structure and Staffing of Programs (Women's Studies Newsletter), undated (Box 12)
  - , Identity and Expression: A Writing Course for Women, undated (Box 12)
  - , Misc., undated (Box 12)
  - Howells, J. G., Fallacies in Childcare II. That Fathering is Unimportant, undated (Box 12)
  - Hughes,, Marija Matich, And then there were Two, undated (Box 12)
  - Hulcoop, John F., Virginia Woolf's Diaries: Some Reflections after Reading Them and a censure of Mr. Hulroyd, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Hurwitz, Edith, Zora Neal Hurston: A Black Woman and her Culture, undated (Box 12)
  - , Elizabeth Pease Nichol, Cornell University and the Anglo-American World of Friendship and Values, undated (Box 12)
  - Husbands, Sandra Acker, Women's Place in Higher Education?, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Jacklin, Carol Nagy and Maccoby, Eleanor E., Sex Differences in Intellectual Abilities: A Reassessment and a Look at some New Explanations, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Jackson, Jacquelyne, Where are the Black Men?, undated (Box 12)
  - Jacobson, Beverly and Wendy, A Look at Women in Medicine, 1975 (Box 12)
  - James, Estelle, Income and Employment Effects of Integration and Education Equality, 1971 (Box 12)
  - James, Selma, Misc., undated (Box 12)
  - Jenkins, Gary L., Women in the Work Force, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Joesting, Joan, Future Problems of Gifted Girls, 1970 (Box 12)
  - , The Changing Role of Women as Free Responsible Agents in Society, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Allan, A Caveat on Reading Tables, undated (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Almeta A., Problems of the Natural Child in Ohio, undated (Box 13)
  - Johnson, Colleen, Women in a Cross-Cultural Perspective, undated (Box 13)
  - Johnson, Jean O., The Role of the Faculty in Academica, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Johnston, John Jr., Sex Discrimination Bylaw: A Study in Judicial Perspective, undated (Box 13)
  - Jones, Beverly and Brown, Judith, Toward a Female Liberation Movement, undated (Box 13)
  - Jordan, Gretchen Graf, Experience and Expression of the Feminine in 20th Century Fiction, undated (Box 13)
  - Jourard, Sidney M., Some Lethal Aspects of the Male Role, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Judd, Elizabeth, Influential Women in Anglo-Saxon England, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Julty, Solomon, A Case of 'Sexual Dysfunction', 1972 (Box 13)
  - Justin, Dena, From Mother Goddess to Dishwasher, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Kagan, Jerome, The Emergence of Sex Differences, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Kahn, Coppelia, Tenants to their Shame": The Rape in Shakespeare's Lucrece, undated (Box 13)
  - Kahn, Robert, From Social Fact to Social Action…, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Kathan, Nancy Lee, Sylvia Plath: Woman of Verse - Woman of Madness, undated (Box 13)
  - Katz, Michael, Occupational Classification in History, undated (Box 13)
  - Kaufman, D and Francis, B, Achievement and Women: The Psychological and Sociological Perspectives, undated (Box 13)
  - Kay, Herma Hill, Marriage, Legal Aspects, 1972 (Box 13)
  - , Divorce Reform, undated (Box 13)
  - Kearns, Karen, The Great Toy Shuck, undated (Box 13)
  - Keck, Donna, The Art of Maiming, undated (Box 13)
  - , Women, undated (Box 13)
  - Keifer, Mariam G and Cullen, Dallas M., Women who Discriminate against other Women: The Process of Denial, undated (Box 13)
  - Keith, Jeff, My Own Men's Liberation, undated (Box 13)
  - Kelman, Steven, A Nonchalant Revolution: Sweden's Liberated Men and Women, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Kent, Martha, Evaluation and Emotion in Child Rearing, 1974 (Box 13)
  - , Research Proposal, undated (Box 13)
  - , Research Proposal, undated (Box 13)
  - , Higher Education and Gender Role Socialization, undated (Box 13)
  - , Almus Pater: 'fair Harvard' and the Graduate Women, undated (Box 13)
  - , The Higher the Fewer, undated (Box 13)
  - , Preliminary Report on the Status of Graduate Women: University of California, Berkeley, undated (Box 13)
  - Key, Mary Ritchie, Linguistic Behavior of Male and Female, undated (Box 13)
  - Khane, Hilda, The Future of Marriage, Family and Children, with a Postscript on Sexuality, 1976 (Box 13)
  - Kiefer, Barry, The Biological Basis of Sex Differences, undated (Box 14)
  - Kirby, Frederick, The Housewife and the Economist, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Kirkendall, Lester A., Toward Clarification of the Concept of Male Sex Drive, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Klemesrud, Judy, A World View of Condition of Women, 1975 (Box 14)
  - , Feminist Shareholders Challenge the Corporate Structure, undated (Box 14)
  - Knapp, Joan, Women and the Creative Process, undated (Box 14)
  - Knox, William E. and Kupferer, Harriet J., A Discontinuity in the Socialization of Males in the United States, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Koedz, Anne, The Myth of the Vaginal Orgasm, undated (Box 14)
  - Kohlberg, Lawrence, Early Education: A Cognitive-Developmental View, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Komanovsky, Mirra, Cultural Contradictions and Sex Roles: The Masculine Case, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Komisar, Lucy, Violence and the Masculine Mystique, undated (Box 14)
  - , Certainly if this country can Vietnamize the war in Southeast Asia, it should not be impossible to Europeanize the Defense of Europe, undated (Box 14)
  - Koonz, Claudia, The Politics of Working Class Women in the Weimar Republic, undated (Box 14)
  - , After the Vote: Women and 'The Woman Question' in Weimar Politics, undated (Box 14)
  - Kotelchuck, Milton, The Nature of the Infant's Tie to His Father, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Kotelchuck, Ronda, The Influence of Architecture and Planning Upon the Woman, undated (Box 14)
  - Kuhn, Maggie, The Gray Panthers, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Kunnlein, Joellyn, The Rubber-Nipple Bottle, undated (Box 14)
  - Kusnetz, Ella, Doris Lessing: Child of Violence, undated (Box 14)
  - Labor-US Department of Labor, Why Women Work, undated (Box 14)
  - Lamm, Bob, Images of Masculinity in Contemporary American, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Langer, Elinor and O'Neill, William and Richardson, Dorothy, Inside the New York Telephone Company - The New York Review, undated (Box 14)
  - Langer, Elinor, The Women of the Telephone Company, undated (Box 14)
  - Lasch, Christopher, Psychiatry as Popular Religion, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Latham, Patricia, Images of Femaleness in the Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century English Novel, undated (Box 14)
  - Laura X, Women's History Research Center, Inc. Berkeley, California, undated (Box 14)
  - Lausti, Tapani, An Attempt to Outline Features of the Discussion About Women and Family in Finland, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Lauter, Paul and Alexander, Archibald W., ACE: Defender of the Educational Faith, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Lacunae Shibboleths, Jewish Long Laws, undated (Box 15)
  - Laws, Judith L., Toward A Model of Female Sexual Identity, 1971 (Box 15)
  - , Feminist Perspectives on Marital Happiness, undated (Box 15)
  - , A Feminist Analysis of Relative Deprivation in Academic Women, undated (Box 15)
  - Leavitt, Ruby R., Aboriginal Woman: Male and Female Anthropological Perspectives, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Leder, Kit, Women in Communes, undated (Box 15)
  - Lebowitz, Arleen, Education and the Allocation of Women's Time, undated (Box 15)
  - LeMasters, E. E., The Passing of the Dominant Husband-Father, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Leonard, Walter, De Funis v. Odegaard: An Invitation to Look Backward, undated (Box 15)
  - Lerner, Gerda, Black and White Women in Interaction and Confrontation, undated (Box 15)
  - , The Lady and the Mill Girl: Changes in the Status of Women in the Age of Jackson, undated (Box 15)
  - , Woman's Rights and American Feminism, undated (Box 15)
  - , On the Teaching and Organization of Feminist Studies, undated (Box 15)
  - Lessing, Doris, Doris Lessing Newsletter, 1976 (Box 15)
  - Lester, Richard A., The Fallacies of Numerical Goals, undated (Box 15)
  - Levine, Stan, One Man's Experience, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Levine, Edward, Equality and Rationalization v. Child Socialization: A Conflict of Interests, undated (Box 15)
  - Levitan, Teresa and Quinn, Robert P. and Staines, Graham L., Sex Discrimination Against the American Working Woman, undated (Box 15)
  - Levy, Betty, The School's Role in the Sex-Role Stereotyping of Girls: A Feminist Review of the Literature, undated (Box 15)
  - Lewandaski, Christine, The Evolving Status of Women in Society: With Concentration on Their Economic Roles in the Pre-Industrial City, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Lewis, Michael, Parents and Children: Sex-Role Development, 1972 (Box 15)
  - , Self, Other, and Fear: Infants' Reactions to People, undated (Box 15)
  - Lieberman, Janet, A Short History of Contraception, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Lieberman, Marcia, Some Day My Prince Will Come: Female Acculturation Through the Fairy Tale, undated (Box 15)
  - , Madame Bovary' and the Cult of Romantic Love, undated (Box 15)
  - , Male Writers and the Double Standard, undated (Box 15)
  - Lieberman, Phil, Physiology and Sex-Linked Behavior, undated (Box 15)
  - Linner, Birgitta, What Does Equality Between the Sexes Imply?, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Linton, Sally, Male/Female Status, Role and Temperment, undated (Box 16)
  - Lipman, Eugene, Women's Liberation and Jewish Tradition, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Lipman-Blumen, Jean, Changing Sex Roles in American Culture: Future Directions for Research, 1972 (Box 16)
  - , How Ideology Shapes Women's Lives, 1975 (Box 16)
  - , Ideology, Social Structure and Crisis: The Case of the Feminist Movement, 1974 (Box 16)
  - , Marriage, Divorce and Occupational Trends Associated with World War II: A Crisis Framework Applied to the Macro-Structural Family Changes, undated (Box 16)
  - , Participation of Women in the Educational Research Community, 1975 (Box 16)
  - , Problems Involved in Interdisciplinary Research on Sex Roles, 1974 (Box 16)
  - , Role De-Differentiation as a System Response to Crisis: Occupational and Political Roles of Women, undated (Box 16)
  - , A Sociological Perspective on Emerging Health Care Roles: A Paradigm for New Occupational Roles, 1975 (Box 16)
  - , The Structure of Inequality: Female Role Ideology and Educational Aspiration, 1971 (Box 16)
  - , The Vicarious Achievement Ethic and Non-Traditional Roles for Women, 1973 (Box 16)
  - , Vicarious and Direct Achievement Patterns in Adulthood, undated (Box 16)
  - , The Dialectic between Research and Social Policy, 1974 (Box 16)
  - , The Development and Impact of Female Role Ideology, 1972 (Box 16)
  - , Demographic Trends and Issues in Women's Health, 1975 (Box 16)
  - , Crisis and Emerging Health Care Roles: Their Impact on Women and Other Minorities, 1975 (Box 16)
  - , Changing Sex Roles: Their Implications for Family Structure, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Lipmen-Blumen and Tickameyer, Ann R., Sex Roles in Transition: A Ten-Year Perspective, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Lithoff, Judy, Midwifery in America, 1860-1930, undated (Box 16)
  - Littlefield, Neil O., Sex-based Discrimination and Credit Granting Practices, 1972-3 (Box 17)
  - Loewenberg, Peter, Emotional Problems of Graduate Education, 1969-72 (Box 17)
  - Lopata, Helena Z., The Social Invowement of American Widows, undated (Box 17)
  - Luce, Ralph A., From Hero to Robot: Masculinity in America - Stereotype and Reality, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Lurie, Alison, Fairy Tale Liberation, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Lutzker, Edythe, Medical Education for Women in Great Britain, undated (Box 17)
  - , Misc., undated (Box 17)
  - Lydon, Susan, Understanding Orgasm, undated (Box 17)
  - Lynn, David B., Determinants of Intellectual Growth in Women, 1972 (Box 17)
  - , Determinants of Sex Differences in Intellectual Development, undated (Box 17)
  - , The Process of Learning Parental and Sex Role Indentification, undated (Box 17)
  - , Sex Differences in Indentification Development, undated (Box 17)
  - Maccoby, Eleanor, Is There Any Way of Thinking, Feeling, or Acting that is Characteristically Female?, undated (Box 17)
  - , Sex Differences in Intellectual Functioning, undated (Box 17)
  - Maccoby, Eleanor and Jacklin, Carol Nagy, Comments on Etiology of Sex Differences, 1972 (Box 17)
  - , On the Alleged Passivity of Women, undated (Box 17)
  - McCall, Dorothy Kaufman, The Second Sex and Jean-Paul Satre: Is Existentialism a Feminism?, undated (Box 17)
  - McCall, Raymond S., MMPI Factors that Differentiate Remediably from Irremediably Obese Women, undated (Box 17)
  - McDaniel, Mary F., Children's Concept of Intelligence and Job Performance as it relates to Gender, 1971 (Box 17)
  - McDonald, Donald, "The Liberation of Women" The Center Magazine, 1972 (Box 17)
  - McGovern, James R., David Graham Phillips and the Virility Impulse of Progressives, 1966 (Box 17)
  - McIntyre, Charshee, African Values versus European Values and their Historical Treatment and Significance, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Maglin, Nana, Una Golden, Carol Kennicott, Ann Vickers: Women in Three Sinclair Lewis Novels, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Mailer, Norman, "The Prisoner of Sex" Harper's Magazine, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Mainardi, Pat, The Politics of Housework, undated (Box 17)
  - Male -> Female VAL, Misc. Documents, undated (Box 18)
  - Mandelbaum, Leonard, Apollo: How the United States Decided to Go to the Moon, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Mandel, Joan D., Women's Liberation: Humanizing rather than Polarizing, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Manis, Jean and Hoffman, Lois, Fertility Motivations and Career Conflicts in Educated Women, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Marlowe, Leigh, Prejudice Against Women in the University, undated (Box 18)
  - , Women in Policing: A Discussion, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Marmor, Judd, Changing Patterns of Masculinity and Femininity, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Mason, Karen and Czajka, John and Arber, Sara, Change in U.S. Women's Sex Role Attitudes 1964-1974, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Mead, Margaret, "Future Family" Trans-action, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Mednick, Martha T., Social Change and Sex-role Inertia: The Case of the Kibbutz, undated (Box 18)
  - Mehrhof, Barbara and Cronan, Sheila, The Rise of Man-The Origins of Women's Oppression: One View, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Men and Masculinity, Men and Masculinity- Center for Women's and Family Living Education, 1971 (Box 18)
  - , "I never set out to Rape Anyone" Ms., 1972 (Box 18)
  - Miller, Casey and Swift, Kate, "De-sexing the English Language" Ms., 1972 (Box 18)
  - Miller, Derek, "Positive and Adverse Effects of the Feminist Movement on Young Children" Medical Aspects of Human Sexuality, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Miller, Lindsay, "Women's Studies" New York Post, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Miller, S. M., "On Men: The Making of a Confused Middle-Class Husband, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Miller, Thomas, Male Self-esteem and Attitudes Towards Women's Roles, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Millet, Kate, Sex, Politics, and the New Feminism (3 folders), 1968 (Box 18)
  - , "The Politics of Sex: Kate Millet of Women's Lib" Time, 1970 (Box 18)
  - , Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18)
  - , "Token Learning: A Study of Women's Higher Education in America" NOW, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Milner, Esther, The Rise and Fall of Feminism, 1970 (Box 18)
  - , "Extreme Cultural Discontinuity and Contemporary American Adolescent Behavior: A Relational Analysis" International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Minault, Gail, Muslim Women in Conflict with Parda: Their Role in the Indian Nationalist Movement, undated (Box 18)
  - Mintz, Ellen and others, Voluntary Kinship Groups: An Alternative to the Nuclear Family, undated (Box 19)
  - Mintz, Ellen, The Prejudice of Parents, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Mischel, Walter, A Social-Learning View of Sex Differences in Behavior, undated (Box 19)
  - Mitchell, Juliet, Women: The Longest Revolution, undated (Box 19)
  - Moers, Ellen, Money, the Job and Little Women, undated (Box 19)
  - Mohan, Pandiri Sarasvati, Miscellaneous (Sanskrit Materials), undated (Box 19)
  - Money, John and Ehrhardt, Anke, Gender Dimorphic Behavior and Fetal Sex Hormones, 1972 (Box 19)
  - , Fetal Hormones and the Brain: Effect on Sexual Dimorphism of Behavior - A Review, 1971 (Box 19)